Guide to the National Coalition for Haitian Rights Records, 1964-2020, bulk 1982-2004 RL.11314
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Print Materials, 1935-2008, undated; bulk 1980-2006; 1
  - Reports, 1935-2006, undated; 4
    - WASH Field Report No. 2 "Haiti", 1980 (Box 216)
    - WASH Field Report No. 213, 1987 (Box 216)
    - WASH Field Report No. 258, 1989 (Box 216)
    - WASH Field Report No. 77, 1983 (Box 216)
    - WASH Field Report No. 96, 1983 (Box 216)
    - Who can deny Haiti assistance?, 1993 (Box 216)
    - working articles for Haiti Insight, 1992 (Box 216)
  - Scholarly Materials, 1974-2005, undated; 5
    - A Framework for World Bank Involvement in Post-Conflict Reconstruction report, 1997 (Box 217)
    - A Statement of the Laws of Haiti in Matters Affecting Business, Third Edition, by T. Richard and F. Latortue, 1974 (Box 217)
    - Abstracts & Sources, 1993-1998, undated (Box 217)
    - Advocate's Guide to IRCA Employment Discrimination, 1992 (Box 217)
    - AIDS prevention for factory women workers, 1988 (Box 217)
    - All in the Same Boat? Unity and Diversity in Haitian Organizing in New York, by N. Schiller et al., 1987 (Box 217)
    - Bibliography of Haitian Law, compiled by Nadege Constant, 1997 (Box 217)
    - Building Skills for Knowledge-Driven Growth, book chapter, undated (Box 217)
    - Caribbean Immigrants & Housing in New York City, by Josh Dewind., 1981 (Box 217)
    - Center for Latin American Studies bibliography on Haiti, 1985 (Box 217)
    - Collection pour l'Etat de Droit en Haiti: Etat de Droit, Justice et Institutions, Haiti Solidarite Internationale, 1994 (Box 217)
    - Council on Foreign Relations, reports prepared for Center for Preventive Action, fourth annual conference, 1997 (Box 217)
    - Criminal Justice & the Role of Sentencing, reports + papers from a conference, 1994 (Box 217)
    - Developing a National Haitian-American Agenda: Moving Forward Together, 2002 (Box 217)
    - Effective Implementation: key to Development Impact, Portfolio Management Task Force (aka Wapenhans report), 1992 (Box 217)
    - Essay Analyzing accomplishments of CHADEL under Jean-Jacques Honorat's direction, 1991 (Box 217)
    - Ethical Perspectives Statement by the Ethical Culture Movement, monograph, undated (Box 217)
    - Haiti Ain't No Panama, Jack, case study by John T. Fishell, undated (Box 217)
    - Haiti Economy v. Puerto Rico: Socio-Economic Plan for Haiti, 1994 (Box 217)
    - Haiti Papers, 2003 (Box 218)
    - Haiti Pour Haiti poems by Astoria Red, 1993 (Box 218)
    - Haiti Study Groups Info Circular, 1995 (Box 218)
    - Haitian Studies Association Proceedings, First Annual Conference, 1989 (Box 218)
    - Haitian Studies Association, 8th Annual Conference Program, 1996 (Box 218)
    - Human Rights Quarterly: Fifteen Truth Commissions - 1974 to 1994: a comparative study (Box 218)
    - Institute for National Strategic Studies, "...Bureaucratic Arrangements in the United Nations Secretariat", 1996 (Box 218)
    - Institute for National Strategic Studies, Somalia Operations: Lessons Learned, 1995 (Box 218)
    - Is There a North America? Conference materials, 1994 (Box 218)
    - Jennifer Berger report, 1990 (Box 218)
    - Klea-A-1-3, 1990 (Box 218)
    - Labor relations in Haiti under the Aristide government, 1992 (Box 218)
    - Making Peace Work: Lessons for the International Development Community conference report, 1996 (Box 218)
    - Media initiative mailing (news articles), 1994 (Box 218)
    - Migration Policy Institute Conference regarding the Interception & Rescue at Sea, papers + agenda, 2005 (Box 218)
    - New Developments in Haiti, statement of J. McCalla at CUSAAC, 1991 (Box 218)
    - North South Center, Multilateral Approaches to Peacemaking & Democratization in the Hemisphere, 1996 (Box 218)
    - Paper of labor in Haiti, 1991 (Box 219)
    - Professionalism in War Reporting, 1998 (Box 219)
    - Refugees as Rescuees - the Tampa Problem, by Erik Rosoeg, 2002 (Box 219)
    - Scholarly articles on Haiti, 1996-1998, undated (Box 219)
    - Speech by Ginette Cherubin, 1996 (Box 219)
    - Strategic & Combat Studies Institute, 1996 (Box 219)
    - Structural Determinants of the Haitian Refugee Movement: Different Interpretations, by Alex Stepick, 1981 (Box 219)
    - The "Failed State" & International Law, by D. Thurer in International Review of Red Cross, N. 836, 1991 (Box 219)
    - The Field Management of Multi-Dimensional Peace Operations: An Analysis of UNOSOM and UNMIH, 1995 (Box 219)
    - The Haitian Migration to South Florida, 1984 (Box 219)
    - The Haitian Refugee Crisis: A Quest for Human Rights, by Thomas D. Jones, Michigan Journal of International Law, 1993 (Box 219)
    - The International Center for Migration, Ethnicity & Citizenship, "Immigrants as Workers in New York City", 1996 (Box 219)
    - The Making of Human Rights Policy in Argentina: The Impact of Ideas and Interests on a legal conflict, undated (Box 219)
    - The Project Cycle, by Warren Baum, 1982 (Box 219)
    - The third epidemic in the Caribbean- Views on AIDS in Haiti, 1991 (Box 219)
    - The United Nations System at Work in Haiti, student paper, 1987 (Box 219)
    - The US Government Program of Intercepting & Forcibly Returning Haitian Boat People to Haiti, 1993 (Box 219)
    - The US Military/NGO Relationship in Humanitarian Interventions, Peacekeeping Institute, 1996 (Box 219)
    - The Venezuelan Blame Game, by R. Christopher Whalen, 1995 (Box 219)
    - The World Economy in Transition. Prospects for Sustainability, Equity & Prosperity, 1993 (Box 219)
    - Toward a Reflection of citizenship, Democracy, and Civil Society: Haitian Women's struggles during 1980-1990, 1994 (Box 219)
    - Unintended Consequences: Rejecting Haitian Boat People & Destabilizing Duvalier, Alex Stepick, 1992-1993 (Box 219)
    - US Army War College Syllabi, 1995-1996 (Box 219)
    - West Indian Domestic Workers, undated (Box 219)
    - When Diplomacy Is Not Enough: Managing Multinational Military Intervention, 1996 (Box 219)
    - William G. O'Neill, College of Kent College of Law, discussion paper, 1998 (Box 219)
- William O'Neill Files, 1990-2000, bulk 1990-1993; 4; 6 boxes
  William (Bill) O'Neill consulted for NCHR. O'Neill served for six months as a senior human rights officer with the first UN Mission deployed in Haiti, known then as the UN/OAS Human Rights Observer Mission, deployed in early 1993. O'Neill, along with Juny McCalla, Ian Martin, Ken Roth, and a few others, designed the Mission and helped implement it.
  Series is arrnaged into two subseries. The Other subseries documents the work of the 1993 UN Mission to Haiti, in addition to O'Neill's work on immigration issues. The Rwanda subseries contains material related to O'Neill's unrelated work on Rwanda.
  - Rwanda, 1993-2000; 17; 3 boxes
    - Report on human rights violations and facilitating factors, 1993 (Box 25)
    - Field activities related to human rights, 1994 (Box 25)
    - Prosecution for crime of genocide and crime against humanity: legal basis, 1995 (Box 25)
    - Wilton Park Conference, Human Rights of the UN System (incl. William O'Neill on human rights monitoring), 1995 (Box 25)
    - Investigation Procedures, 1995-1996 (Box 25)
    - Prison and justice system changes, 1995-1996 (Box 25)
    - Faults in the justice system for genocide trials, 1995-1997 (Box 25)
    - Government of Rwanda opposes UN resolution, 1996 (Box 25)
    - Human Rights in Modern Peacekeeping (Bill O'Neill), 1996 (Box 25)
    - Intimidation of judicial officers, 1996 (Box 25)
    - People and material goods security, 1996 (Box 25)
    - Report on punishment for children accused of genocide crimes, 1996 (Box 25)
    - Status of NGO and freedom of association in Ethiopia, 1996 (Box 25)
    - William G. O'Neill papers, 1996 (Box 25)
    - Letters on ICTR, 1996-1997 (Box 26)
    - Briefing notes, 1997 (Box 26)
    - Contact lists, 1997 (Box 26)
    - Deterioration of the security and human rights situation in Ruhengeri Prefecture, 1997 (Box 26)
    - End of mission report, 1997 (Box 26)
    - Genocide trial approach, 1997 (Box 26)
    - Human Rights in Congo and Western Rwanda, 1997 (Box 26)
    - Human Rights situation in Rwanda and HRFOR activities, 1997 (Box 26)
    - IRIN emergency update on the Great Lakes, 1997 (Box 26)
    - IRIN update for Central and Eastern Africa, 1997 (Box 26)
    - Killings by armed group in Mutura, 1997 (Box 26)
    - Killings of persons attempting to evade from the custody of State agents, 1997 (Box 26)
    - Lester B. Pearson Canadian Int'l Peacekeeping Training Centre, PPC materials, 1997 (Box 26)
    - Meeting notes, 1997 (Box 26)
    - News articles on UN mission, 1997 (Box 27)
    - O'Neill mission for the lawyers committee for Human Rights, 1997 (Box 27)
    - Organization of the Tribunal, 1997 (Box 27)
    - PPC- Human Rights course, 1997 (Box 27)
    - Prosecuting the genocide in Rwanda, 1997 (Box 27)
    - Reports on killings in Ruhengeri prefecture, 1997 (Box 27)
    - Reposition human rights situation in Rwanda, 1997 (Box 27)
    - Rwanda evaluation mission and recommendations, 1997 (Box 27)
    - Statement by Mary Robinson, UN High Commissioner for Human Rights, 1997 (Box 27)
    - Support to the Justice System, 1997 (Box 27)
    - Towards an integrated and coherent UN system in the Great Lakes Region, 1997 (Box 27)
    - Trials for Kanama incidents, 1997 (Box 27)
    - UN report to the government of Rwanda, 1997 (Box 27)
    - Rebuilding a new Rwanda by UNDP, c. 1997 (Box 27)
    - Human rights reports and Human Rigths Field Operations activities, 1997-1998 (Box 27)
    - UN Human Rights report for Rwanda and Congo, 1998 (Box 27)
    - Chairman Peace Operation Seminar, 2000 (Box 27)
    - International Association of Peace Keeping Centers, 2000 (Box 27)
  - Other O'Neill Files, 1990-1998; 18; 4 boxes
    - United Nations O'Neill Files, 1990 (Box 27)
      [French] [English]
    - United Nations O'Neill Files, 1991 (Box 28)
    - United Nations O'Neill Files, 1992 (Box 28)
    - United Nations O'Neill Files, 1993 (Box 28)
    - Church World Service, 1996 (Box 28)
    - UN Human Rights Commission China draft, 1996 (Box 28)
    - United Nations O'Neill Files, 1996 (Box 28)
    - Affidavit of support, 1997 (Box 28)
    - Board of Education lawsuit, 1997; 1 of 2 (Box 28)
    - Board of Education lawsuit, 1997; 2 of 2 (Box 28)
    - Letter to Pierre and Josh, 1997 (Box 28)
    - National Immigration Law Center materials, 1997 (Box 28)
    - UN Exercises, 1997 (Box 29)
    - National Citizenship Network binder, 1998; 1 of 2 (Box 29)
    - National Citizenship Network binder, 1998; 2 of 2 (Box 29)
    - NILC- Immigrants and Welfare resource manual, 1998; 1 of 2 (Box 29)
    - NILC- Immigrants and Welfare resource manual, 1998; 2 of 2 (Box 29)
    - NY Immigration Coalition binder, 1998; 1 of 2 (Box 30)
    - NY Immigration Coalition binder, 1998; 2 of 2 (Box 30)
    - "Haverford College Sweat-Free Code of Conduct" draft, undated (Box 30)
    - "Towards a Consistent Strategy for Human Rights Advocacy in Egypt", undated (Box 30)
    - Central American articles, undated (Box 30)
- Subject Files, 1964-2008, undated; bulk 1980-2006; 5; 89 boxes
  The Subject Files series is the largest series in the collection, documenting a wide variety of NCHR's work in Haiti, the US, and the Caribbean. Important sections include files on individuals such as Jean-Bertrand Aristide and Prosper Avril, Haitian migrant workers in the Bahamas and the Dominican Republic, "Boat People" and interdiction, elections and judicial reform in Haiti, Guantanamo and Krome detention centers, police reform, HIV and AIDS, other human rights groups working in Haiti including Caribbean Rights, the Haitian Center for Human Rights (CHADEL), Komité National du Kongrés des Mouvements Démocratiques(KONAKOM), Ligue des Anciens Prisonniers Politiques Haïtiens(LAPPH), and Physicians for Human Rights. The Subject Files series may overlap with many of the other series in the collections.
  - "A Call for Further Action in Support of Haiti's Persecuted Press", 1992 (Box 65)
  - "A Call for Solidarity with Haitian Journalists", 1992 (Box 65)
  - "A Case to be Solved by the International Community" - Contras, 1991 (Box 65)
  - "A Different Reality: the Central American refugee and the lawyer", undated (Box 65)
  - "A Directory of Haitianists", 1985 (Box 65)
  - "A Round of applause for Radio Liberte", 1993 (Box 65)
  - "A Second Chance at Life" - Yolande Jean, 1993 (Box 65)
  - "A Statement by the American Friends Service Committee", 1993 (Box 65)
  - "A Temporary Workers Program for the US", 1983 (Box 65)
  - "A Week in Haiti", 1998 (Box 65)
  - "A week in the life of Haiti Cherie", 1999 (Box 65)
  - "Access to Justice: The NYPD and the Haitian Community", 2004 (Box 65)
  - "Agreement on Human Rights", 1991 (Box 65)
  - "Analyse de la situation politique Haitienne" "Analysis of the Haitian Political Situation", 1985 (Box 65)
  - "Arrest of Numerous Haitian Citizens", 1994 (Box 65)
  - "At the Crossroads- Haitian Migration and Refugee Policy", 1995 (Box 65)
  - "Banking on the Tenth Department", 1991 (Box 65)
  - "Beyond the Bateyes", 1996 (Box 65)
  - "Children and Young Adults Experiencing Problems with the Visa Section of the US Embassy in Haiti", 1993 (Box 65)
  - "Crime and Justice in the Caribbean", 1991 (Box 65)
  - "Declaration of Senators and Deputees", 1991 (Box 65)
  - "Dellums Urges UN and OAS to restore the government of Haiti", 1991 (Box 65)
  - "Democratic Situation and Human Rights in Haiti", 1993 (Box 65)
  - "Do Sye Sou Chef Sek Syon Fe Dera Syon tet Kole ti Peyizan Latibonit", 1989 (Box 65)
  - "Doublebacker" refugee affidavits, 1992 (Box 65)
  - "El Congo" News on Haiti election, 1996 (Box 65)
  - "Emergency European Agency Consultation on Haiti", 1991 (Box 65)
  - "Erase Racism", 1992 (Box 65)
  - "Executive Summary- Sanctions in Haiti", 1993 (Box 65)
  - "Farmworkers" NCHR report by Mary Goodman, 1987 (Box 65)
  - "For an Economy on the Human Face", 1988 (Box 65)
  - "For Better Management of the Question of Immigration", 1994 (Box 65)
  - "Forced or Involuntary Disappearances in Central America", 1991 (Box 65)
  - "Forum Bateys: the present and the future", 1992 (Box 65)
  - "Haiti and the New World Order" draft, 1994 (Box 65)
  - "Haiti Imprisons 6 Deportees", 1990 (Box 65)
  - "Haiti- reforms draw US praise", 1980 (Box 65)
  - "Haiti: Darkness Remains", 1995 (Box 65)
  - "Haiti: Justice Imprisoned", 1991 (Box 66)
  - "Haiti: military mutiny", 1991 (Box 66)
  - "Haiti: the challenges of restoring Human Rights and Democracy", 1993 (Box 66)
  - "Haitian Refugee Policy", 1992 (Box 66)
  - "Haitians Deported by INS are jailed in Haiti", undated (Box 66)
  - "Haitians Deported by INS are jailed in Haiti", 1990 (Box 147)
  - "Honor the Memory of the Refugee Ship St. Louis", 1992 (Box 66)
  - "How Stella Got Her Groove Back", 1998 (Box 66)
  - "How Stella Got Her Groove Back", 1998 (Box 72)
  - "Human Rights Concerns in Haiti", 1994 (Box 66)
  - "Human Rights Group Calls for Haiti Election Delay", 1999 (Box 66)
  - "Human Rights Groups Condemn Haitian Army Attacks", 1994 (Box 66)
  - "Human Rights in Haiti Since the Installation of Leslie Manigat", 1988 (Box 66)
  - "Immigration Enforcement and Asylum Reform Act", 1993; 1 of 2 (Box 66)
  - "Immigration Enforcement and Asylum Reform Act", 1993; 2 of 2 (Box 66)
  - "Improving Prison Conditions in the Caribbean", 1991 (Box 66)
  - "In Country Processing is No Solution for Haitian Refugees", 1993 (Box 66)
  - "Institutionalizing Human Rights in Haiti", 1997 (Box 66)
  - "International Norms and Policies on the Human Rights of Prisoners", 1991 (Box 66)
  - "Konbit" - "Working Together", 1991 (Box 66)
  - "La Lettre du MIDH" news, 1987 (Box 66)
  - "Le militant des droits de l'homme", 1987 (Box 148)
  - "Mass Migrations from Haiti and Cuba", 1994 (Box 66)
  - "Messengers of the Resurrected Christ Pastoral Development" proposal, 1990 (Box 66)
  - "Monday": News on refugee and immigration issues, 1990 (Box 66)
  - "Operation December 16", 1991 (Box 66)
  - "Operationalizing the Rhetoric of Synergy", 2005 (Box 66)
  - "Our Hope for our Children" memos, 2003 (Box 66)
  - "Prepared Statement of Father Edwin Paraisan", 1991 (Box 66)
  - "Progress toward Democracy in Haiti", 1991 (Box 66)
  - "Rapd sou Kadejak Mesyedam Koudeta t'ap cheche fe sou Pep Balan an", undated (Box 150)
  - "Refugees: A Challenge to Solidarity", 1993 (Box 66)
  - "Report- Center for Social Research and Diffusion of People", 1986 (Box 66)
  - "Repression of Communal Sections the Case of Labadie", 1989 (Box 66)
  - "Return to Despotism", 1990 (Box 66)
  - "Reverting to Despotism- Human Rights in Haiti", 1990 (Box 67)
  - "Rights Groups Charge Haitian Regime with Systemic and Continuing Repression", 1991 (Box 67)
  - "Rights Groups Condemn Military Violence in Haiti", 1989 (Box 67)
  - "Social Welfare projects in bateys" notes, 1992 (Box 67)
  - "Structures and functions of the State in Haiti", 1986 (Box 67)
  - "Summary of the incident of Five Youths killed in Damas", 1991 (Box 67)
  - "Suppressing Haiti's Courageous Clergy", 1992 (Box 67)
  - "Tet Kole Ti Peyizan Ayisyen", 1991 (Box 67)
  - "The 411 Campaign for Immigrants", 1993 (Box 67)
  - "The Administration of Justice in St. Vincent and the Grenadines", 1990 (Box 67)
  - "The Challenges in Haiti", 1995 (Box 151)
  - "The Church of Haiti during the Regime of Duvalier", 1985 (Box 67)
  - "The Current Political Crisis in Haiti as it is Affecting Grassroots Groups", 1991 (Box 67)
  - "The Dominican Government Must do More to Guarantee the Rights of Haitian Workers", 1990 (Box 67)
  - "The Escape from Hell", 1989 (Box 67)
  - "The Immigration Consequences of Criminal Proceeding", 1984 (Box 67)
  - "The Land Problem in the Artibonite Valley", 1986 (Box 67)
  - "The MDN and the exit of Franck Romain", 1989 (Box 67)
  - "The Plight of the Haitian Refugees" NCHR, 1985 (Box 67)
  - "The Point", 1997 (Box 67)
  - "The Respect of Human Rights", 1990 (Box 67)
  - "The Save Program", 1983 (Box 67)
  - "The Situation of Haitians in the Caribbean", 1994 (Box 67)
  - "The Syndical Movement Situation under Jean Claude Duvalier", 1985 (Box 67)
  - "The Twain Meet: Natural Disaster and Foreign Policy", 1992 (Box 67)
  - "Three Human Rights Organizations Condemn the Imprisonment of Haitians in Dominican", 1989 (Box 67)
  - "Two Years After the Coup: Haiti's Media Under Attack", 1993 (Box 67)
  - "Uncertainty in the Days of Administration Change", 1996 (Box 67)
  - "US Policy since Avril", 1990 (Box 67)
  - 11/1/89 arrest notes, 1989 (Box 67)
  - 12/16 Day of Reconciliation in South Africa, 1997 (Box 132)
  - 12-mile limit and violations, 1989 (Box 67)
  - 12-mile limit proclamation, 1988 (Box 67)
  - 1990 Census Complete Count Committee, 1989 (Box 67)
  - 2003 National Haitian Lawyers List (Box 67)
  - 44th Session- Commission for Social Development, 2006 (Box 67)
  - 8th Pan-African Assembly, Lome, 2002 (Box 68)
  - A Program on Accountability for Human Rights Crimes in Haiti, 1994 (Box 68)
  - A.I. urgent action, 1988 (Box 68)
  - ABA Materials, 1994 (Box 68)
  - ABA proposed Rule of Law Correspondence/letter, 1994 (Box 68)
  - ABA-Honorat Campaign, 1991-1992 (Box 68)
  - Abner Louima, 1997-1998 (Box 68)
  - Accord, 1992 (Box 68)
  - Accord Tripartite, 1992 (Box 68)
  - Account of arrests and shootings in Carrefour, 1990 (Box 68)
  - Action Suggestions for Haiti, 1992 (Box 68)
  - Ad hoc meeting of ministers, 1991 (Box 68)
  - Ad Hoc working group on Haitian refugees, 1993 (Box 68)
  - Address: Governor de la Rosee, 2001 (Box 68)
  - Adjustment of Status for Haitian Nationals, 1999 (Box 68)
  - Administration of Justice, 1993 (Box 68)
  - Administration/Ministry of Justice, Haiti, 1996 (Box 68)
  - Admission Numbers Refugee Processing, 1993 (Box 68)
  - Adopt-a-parish program, 1990 (Box 68)
  - Advocacy for Haitian Refugees, 1992 (Box 68)
  - Advocacy Institute, 1993 (Box 68)
  - Advocacy trip in Canada, 1996 (Box 68)
  - Affidavits, 1989 (Box 68)
  - AFL statement to South Africa, 1985 (Box 68)
  - African Friends Service Committee letter, 1987 (Box 148)
  - African Jesuit AIDS Network, 2002 (Box 68)
  - Agence de Développment Economique Intégré (ADECOL), 1989 (Box 68)
  - Agencies Interested in Haiti, from Inter Action, 1994 (Box 150)
  - Agency for International Development, 1994 (Box 68)
  - Agency for International Development Grant, 2002 (Box 68)
  - Agency for International Development invitation for Application, 1991 (Box 68)
  - Agiae Charlot to O'Campo, 1991 (Box 68)
  - Agrarian reform, 1989 (Box 68)
  - Agreement of Human Rights from: UN El Salvador, 1991 (Box 68)
  - Agricultural labor reform, 2002-2003 (Box 68)
  - AHP 283rd resume of Haiti's National News, 1995 (Box 69)
  - Ahpaly Coradin correspondence, 1994 (Box 69)
  - Ahpaly Coradin speaking engagements, 1995 (Box 69)
  - Ahpaly Coradin to McCalla, 1995 (Box 69)
  - AI to Pierre Esperance, 1993 (Box 69)
  - Aid agreement between US Government and Haiti [h], 1990 (Box 69)
  - Aid to HNN members, 1993 (Box 69)
  - AIDS/SIDA, 1990 (Box 147)
  - Alfonse D'Amato to NCHR, 1991 (Box 152)
  - Al-Krome protest, 1990 (Box 147)
  - Alternate Museum Project, 1989 (Box 149)
  - Alternative for a judiciary reform in Haiti [h], 1993 (Box 69)
  - Amb. Jean Casimir speech, 1992 (Box 69)
  - Ambassador Carmen Aniza to Kenneth Roth, 1992 (Box 69)
  - Ambassador of France in Haiti, 1994 (Box 69)
  - Ambassadors from Haiti to Washington on Carhagene talks, 1991 (Box 69)
  - America Online article, 1995 (Box 69)
  - American Council for Nationalities Service, 1989-1990 (Box 69)
  - American Federation of Labor to Hiram Lawrence, 1991 (Box 69)
  - American Friends Committee Mexico/U.S. Border Program minutes from meeting on labor, migrants, and perspectives, 1989 (Box 69)
  - American Friends Service Committee, 1986-1990 (Box 69)
  - American Friends Service Committee, 1999 (Box 69)
  - American Friends Service Committee Visa Lottery, 1996 (Box 69)
  - American Immigrant Lawyer Association (AILA) to President Clinton, 1994 (Box 69)
  - American Jewish Committee, undated (Box 151)
  - American Jewish Committee statement, 1991 (Box 69)
  - Americans for Manno, 1998 (Box 69)
  - Americas Watch, 1990 (Box 132)
  - Americas Watch and NCHR protest letter, 1993 (Box 69)
  - America's Watch position offer to McCalla, 1990 (Box 150)
  - America's Watch report notes, 1989 (Box 125)
  - America's Watch, National Coalition for Haitian Refugees, Caribbean Rights, 1990 (Box 69)
  - America's Watch-Board Meeting Info, 1993 (Box 69)
  - AMH on Dr. Roy, 1990 (Box 69)
  - AMHE Convention, 1998 (Box 69)
  - Amnesty Conference (Long Island), 1993 (Box 69)
  - Amnesty International, 1991; 1 of 2 (Box 69)
  - Amnesty International, 1991; 2 of 2 (Box 69)
  - Amnesty International- "Distribution of Haiti Issue Brief", 1990 (Box 148)
  - Amnesty International News Releases, 1994 (Box 69)
  - Amnesty Program for Undocumented Immigrants, 2000 (Box 69)
  - Amy Wilentz to editor - NY Times, 1991 (Box 69)
  - Amy Wilentz fax to the Times on reporting in Haiti, 1991 (Box 150)
  - ANDP positions, 1990 (Box 69)
  - Andy Levin's Haiti Briefs, 1992 (Box 69)
  - Angola, 1997 (Box 69)
  - Ann Fuller, 1992 (Box 69)
  - Ann Fuller to Gloribel Rubio, 1991 (Box 69)
  - Anna D'Adesky reports, 1992 (Box 69)
  - Anne Fuller- Affidavit, 1992 (Box 69)
  - Anne Fuller correspondence, 1989 (Box 69)
  - Anne Fuller testimony, 1991 (Box 69)
  - Anne Fuller to Francois Benoit, 1990 (Box 69)
  - Anne Fuller to Honrat, 1991 (Box 69)
  - Anne Fuller, memo on Haitian arrests, 1990 (Box 148)
  - Announcement of screening services to apply for refugee status in Port-au-Prince, 1992 (Box 70)
  - Annual report of the Haitian Center for Human Rights, 1989 (Box 70)
  - Anti-Nationalism, 1993 (Box 70)